All right good afternoon everybody
大家下午好
Welcome good to see you all, welcome also to our viewers on video
欢迎大家看到你们，也欢迎观众观看视频
So last week we looked at this virtual memory mechanism
上周我们学习了虚拟内存机制
And how it provides so many different useful functionalities to the system
以及它如何为系统提供如此多的有用功能
Along with this sort of abstraction of having this large contiguous array of bytes
随着这种大型连续字节数组的抽象
Now once we're given that large array of bytes
现在，一旦我们获得了大量的字节
Now we have to manage it
现在我们必须管理它
And we have to have some mechanism to manage and use that resource
我们必须有一些机制来管理和使用该资源
Okay so
可以，然后呢
That's the topic of a lectures this week is a storage allocation
本周讲座的主题是储存器分配
And how storage allocators work
以及储存器分配器的工作原理
And how you use them to manage the matter the virtual memory in your system
以及如何使用它们来管理系统中的虚拟内存
So the basic idea of a dynamic memory allocator
所以动态储存器分配器的基本思想是
Is that applications use it to to manipulate virtual memory to create to allocate and free chunks of virtual memory
应用程序使用它去操纵虚拟内存，去构造、分配以及释放虚拟存储器片
That you need in your program
在你的程序中会需要这些虚拟存储器
And this memory is maintained in an area of virtual memory called the heap
而且这个存储器在称为堆的虚拟存储器区域中被维护
All languages have some mechanism for acquiring and manipulating this dynamic memory
所有语言都有一些用来分配和操纵动态存储器的机制
So in C
所以在 C 中
It's the malloc package. Languages like java have the new method
使用的是 malloc 的方式。但是像 java 这样的语言中使用的是new方法
Now the allocator maintains the heap as a contiguous collection of blocks
分配器将堆维护为连续的块集合
And blocks can be allocated or free
块可以被分配或者被释放
Allocated meaning that they're being used by some program application
被分配意味着它们被某些应用程序使用
Free meaning that there available to be for use by an application
空闲意味着可供应用程序使用
And there's two types of allocators. The kind of allocator that you find in C such as the malloc package
有两种类型的分配器。你在C中找到的那种分配器，比如 malloc 包
It's up to the application to both explicitly allocate the memory
这种分配器，应用程序将决定否是显式分配内存
And explicitly free it when the application is finished with it
并在应用程序完成后是否显式地释放内存
Okay so the system won't free up any memory that you allocate unless you do it
所以系统不会释放你分配的任何内存
Explicitly by calling the free function
除非你通过调用 free 函数显示的释放内存
But there's other languages that support implicit allocators
但是还有其他语言支持隐式分配器
And in these implicit allocators the programmer explicitly allocates memory
在这些隐式分配器中，程序员显式地分配内存
But then the system takes care of freeing the memory
但随后系统负责释放内存
Okay so it's
好的，就是这样
That the burden of freeing the memory is shifted from the application program to the system
释放内存的负担从应用程序转移到系统
And it frees this memory implicitly sort of behind the scenes using a process called garbage collection
并且它使用称为垃圾收集的过程隐式地释放了这些内存
Okay so languages like java,ML,Lisp they all do implicit they all support in close at allocators
所以像 Java, ML, Lisp 这样的语言都支持隐式分配器
Now today we're going to discuss explicit memory allocators
今天我们要讨论一下显式分配器
On Thursday we'll get into implicit allocators and how they work
星期四，我们将进入隐式分配器及其运作方式
Now the allocators in C is provided it by the standard C library in a set of function called malloc package
现在，在 C 语言中的分配器由 C 语言标准库中一组叫做 malloc 包的函数提供
The malloc function is used to allocate memory
malloc 函数用于分配内存
And it takes as input a size argument which is in bytes
它把以字节作为单位的参数作为函数的输入参数
And then it returns a pointer to a memory block that contains at least size bytes
然后它返回一个指向内存块的指针，该内存块至少包含所声明的大小的字节
And that block is aligned on x86 systems to 8-byte on x86-64 systems to 16-byte
并且该块在 x86 系统上以 8 字节对齐，在 x86-64 系统上以 16 字节对齐
If size is 0,it returns null
如果 size 为 0 ，则返回 null
And then it returns -1 like most typical system calls
然后它像大多数典型的系统调用一样返回 -1
The programmer frees memory by calling the free function
程序员通过调用 free  函数释放内存
It takes an argument a pointer that was returned from some prior invocation of malloc
它以一个先前调用 malloc 时返回的指针作为参数
And it returns nothing
并且没有任何返回值
And it frees that
它释放了
I've given this pointer that was returned by the prior indication of malloc
在之前调用 malloc 函数的时候返回的指针
It frees the block at that address
它释放了该地址的块
And then returns that block to the pool of available memory
然后将该块放到可用内存池
Now there's some other functions
现在还有其他一些功能
Calloc is a version of malloc that gives you an initialized block of memory that's initialized to 0
calloc 是 malloc 的另一个版本，它为你提供初始化为 0 的初始化内存块
And realloc. You can malloc a block and then call realloc to change the size of that previously allocated block
你可以 malloc 一个块，然后调用 realloc 来改变以前分配的块的大小
And then there's a function called 'sbrk' which is used internally by allocators to grow and shrink the heap
然后有一个名为 「sbrk」 的函数，分配器在内部使用它来增长和缩小堆
So when an allocator needs more memory
所以当分配器需要更多内存时
It calls sbrk to get that additional virtual memory
它调用「sbrk」来获得额外的虚拟内存
And then that's added to the heap that the portion
然后那个部分添加到堆中
That grows the heap and then it adds it to the memory that the allocator is manipulating
这会使堆增长，然后将其添加到分配器正在操作的内存中
So here's an example of how we would use malloc in a simple program
所以这是一个如何在一个简单的程序中使用 malloc 的例子
We have a pointer to an int 「p」
我们有一个指向整型的指针 「p」
And we call malloc
我们调用 malloc
And we want to allocate an array of n int
我们想要分配一个大小为 n 的整型数组
So this is sort of the standard way you call it
这是我们调用它的标准方式
We want n ints and so we call it with n*sizeof(int)
我们想要 n 个 int，所以我们用 「n * sizeof(int)」 来调用它
Because remember the argument is in bytes
因为参数是以字节为单位
Malloc returns a pointer
malloc 返回一个指针
It returns that generic pointer , void* pointer so
它返回那个泛型指针  ——「void*」 指针
We cast it to a pointer to an int to keep the compiler happy
我们将它转​​换为指向整型的指针，以便于编译器编译
And then assign it to p
然后将其分配给 p
We check for a null return value
我们检查返回值是否为空
So I should point out the it returns 0 on error
所以我应该指出它在出错时返回 0
So we recheck for this null pointer which is 0
所以我们重新检查这个指针是否为空指针
In print an error if it's null
如果它为空，则打印错误
Now once we've got that pointer now p we can treat it just like an array
现在，一旦我们得到了指针，我们就可以像对待数组一样对待它
So inside the loop if we want to initialize it we loop
所以在循环内部如果我们想要初始化它
Across the elements of the array initializing each one to some value
我们可以循环遍历数组的元素，将每个元素初始化为某个值
When we're finished with this chunk of memory that we've allocated, then we free it by calling free with the pointer p
当我们完成了我们分配的这块内存时，我们通过使用指针 p 调用 free 来释放它
Okay now the
好的，现在
So we're going to look today at how functions like malloc and free are implemented
因此，我们今天将看看如何实现 malloc 和 free 等功能
So we're going to make a few simplifying assumptions
所以我们将做一些简化的假设
So I'm going to
所以我要去
Memory it is byte address we know that
我们知道内存的地址是按照字节的地址
But for the purposes of this lecture we're going to assume that it's word address
但是为了本讲座的目的，我们将假设它是字的地址
Okay so we're just going to look at word size units
好的，我们只是关注以字为大小的单位
And I'm going to assume that words are 4 bytes
而且我将假设字是 4 个字节
So they basically are the size of an int
所以他们基本上是一个 int 的大小
So this isn't actually, this isn't true, I need to fix that
所以这实际上这不是正确的，我需要修正它
So basically we're going to think of words as four byte quantity sort of integer size quantities
所以基本上我们会将字视为四字节，这刚好是整数大小
And then blocks or contiguous chunks of those words that can be either allocated or free
这些字所构成的块或者连续的片能够被分配或者被释放
So here we have a portion of the heap
所以这里我们有一部分堆
Which consists of a 4 words allocated block followed by a 2 words free block
其中包括 4 字大小的已被分配的块，后面跟着 2 个字大小的空闲块
Followed by another a 4 words allocated block, followed by a 3 words free block
接下来是另一个 4 字大小的已被分配块，后跟 3 字大小的空闲块
And we'll indicate these free blocks by white and will indicate allocated blocks with some shade of color
我们将使用白色表示这些空闲块，并用某种颜色的阴影来表示已分配块
So let's look now how a sequence of allocations and freeze would work
那么现在让我们看一下一系列的分配和释放是如何工作的
And now notice I'm calling malloc with the size of words
现在注意我正在调用具有字大小的 malloc
Not bytes
不是字节
Just to keep these pictures simpler
只是为了保持这些图片更简单
So in this first we call malloc and allocate of a 4 word block
所以首先我们调用 malloc 并分配一个 4 字大小的块
And that gives us a pointer p1
这给了我们一个指针「p1」
Then we call malloc again to get a 5 words block
然后我们再次调用 malloc 来获得一个 5 字大小的块
So it just takes it one of the free words and allocates it
所以它只需要空闲字中的一部分并分配它
We call malloc again to get a 6 words block
我们再次调用 malloc 来获得一个 6 字大小的块
And then we free the block that's pointed at by p2 this purple block
然后我们释放 「p2」 这个紫色块所指向的块
Okay so now we free up that block
好的，现在我们释放了那块
And then we do another allocation for a 2 words block
然后我们为 2 字大小的块进行另一次分配
And so the the allocator looks to see if it can find a free block that has enough room and
所以分配器去查看否能找到一个有足够空间的空闲块
It finds this free block here that has 5 free words and then it
它在这里找到这个有 5 个字大小的空闲块
Allocates the the requested block inside of that free block
它在该空闲块内分配所请求的块
Now allocators work under a lot of different constraints
现在分配器在很多不同的约束下工作
Okay so it's hard to write an allocator because of all these constraints
因为所有这些限制，编写分配器变得很困难
Applications can choose any combination of allocated and free blocks
应用程序可以将已分配块和空闲块的任意组合
So you can't predict what an application is going to request
因此，你无法预测应用程序请求的内容
And and the application is required to free a block when it frees a block to pass a pointer
在应用程序需要适当一个块的时候被要求去传递一个指针
That was returned from a previous invocation of malloc
这个指针是从之前调用的 malloc 所返回的
Okay so the application has a few constraints,  but
应用程序有一些限制
But really the only one that it has is that the fact that the
但它真正唯一的一个事实是
When it frees something, it has to be a pointer from a previous invocation of malloc
当它释放某些东西时，必须使用来自之前调用 malloc 时所返回的的指针
Now the malloc operates or allocators like malloc operate under a lot of different constraints
malloc 运行或像 malloc 这样的分配器在很多不同的约束条件下运行
They can't control the size or the number of the allocated blocks
它们无法控制分配块的大小或数量
Because they have no control over the what the application is doing
因为他们无法控制应用程序正在做的事情
If an application calls malloc, malloc has to respond right away
如果应用程序调用 malloc ，malloc 必须立即响应
It might you might be able to do a better more efficient version by batching up requests
你可能可以通过批量处理请求来创建更高效​​的版本
And then responding to all those requests at once
然后立即相应所有的请求
But the allocator can't do it. When it gets called it has to process the request and then return right away
分配器无法做到这一点。当它被调用时，它必须处理请求然后立即返回
It has to of course it has to allocate blocks from free memory
它当然必须从可用内存中分配块
So it can't
所以它不能
In general I can't touch any allocated block
一般来说，我无法触及任何已分配的块
Right once it allocates a block,that block belongs to the application and the malloc package can't touch it
一旦它分配了一个块，那么该块就属于那个应用程序，而 malloc 包不能触及它
Now this has a number of implications
这有很多含义
So this means that the allocator can't move blocks around like it
这意味着分配器不能移动块
It can't compress blocks like an allocator might want to take allocated blocks and smoosh them all together
比如分配器无法将已分配的块放到一起以达到压缩块的目的
To create larger free blocks. hey! but it can't do that
这样能创建更大的空闲块。嘿！它不能这样做
Okay so once you know in a language like C once an malloc
在一个语言中，比如 C 语言中的 malloc
Gives a block to an application it can't touch it
为应用程序分配一个块，分配器就无法再触及它
Okay because blocks are holding data structures like structs
因为块正在保存像结构一样的数据结构
Or you know scalar objects it has to be aligned to the size of the largest object that can occur
或者标量对象必须与可能出现的最大对象的大小对齐
Okay so for 64-bit systems that's 16 byte alignment. For 32-bit systems it's 8 byte alignment
所以对于 32 位系统需要 16 位字节对齐。64 位系统，需要 8 字节对齐
Now allocator are really interesting objects
分配器真的很有趣
Because they combine a trade-off of both running time sort of speed and space
因为它包含了时间和空间上的权衡
So it's kind of a space and performance trade-off
所以这是一种空间和性能的权衡
You're trying to optimize both you want it to run as quickly as possible
你正在尝试使其运行得尽可能块
But you wanted to use the virtual memory in the heap as efficiently as possible
但是你希望尽可能高效地使用堆中的虚拟内存
Okay so let's
好的，让我们
We define these sort of speed and memory efficiency metrics
我们定义了这些速度和内存效率指标
We have two metrics that we use, one is called throughput
我们使用了两个指标，一个称为吞吐量
So given some sequence of malloc and free requests - R0 through R(n-1)
因此给出了 malloc 和 free 请求序列 —— R0 到 R(n-1)
So just some where R is either a malloc or free
R 表示 malloc 或 free
Our goal is to maximize throughput
我们的目标是最大化吞吐量
And the peak memory utilization
并且峰值内存利用率
And what makes malloc such a fascinating and interesting study is that these often conflict
而这些经常发生的冲突使得研究 malloc  如此令人着迷和有趣
It's very easy to make a really fast malloc that has terrible memory utilization
编写一个具有很糟糕内存利用率但是很快速的 malloc 非常容易
So throughput is just the number of complete requests per unit time
因此吞吐量只是每单位时间所有的请求的数量
So if we have 5,000 malloc calls and 5,000 free calls in 10 seconds
因此，如果我们在 10 秒钟内调用 5,000 次 malloc 并调用 5,000 次 free
Then a throughput is 1,000 operations/second
然后吞吐量为 1,000 次/秒
So it's just measuring sort of how efficiently are a malloc can process these requests from an application
因此，它只是评价 malloc 处理来自应用程序的这些请求的效率
Now peak memory utilization
峰值内存利用率
Is a measure sort of how much useful space
是一种衡量多少有用空间的标准
So how much it measured how efficiently the allocator uses the heap
它衡量分配器使用堆的效率有多大
Sort of how much is wasted on sort of overheads in the data structures that the allocator has to uses to in the implementation
去衡量分配器在实现中必须使用的数据结构中的各种开销上浪费了多少
So we'll define a payload
所以我们将定义一个有效载荷
When malloc returns a block
当 malloc 返回一个块时
I'm sorry,what an application makes a call to malloc it's requesting a certain size block
对不起，一个应用程序调用 malloc 以请求一定大小的块
And that block is called the payload
该块称为有效载荷
So if we call malloc with an argument of 10 bytes
因此，如果我们使用 10 个字节的参数调用 malloc
We're requesting a block that has a payload that's at least size 10
我们要求一个有效载荷至少为 10 大小的块
And the 10 bytes that we request that are called the payload
我们请求的 10 个字节称为有效负载
Everything else in that block is overhead
该块中的其他所有内容都是开销
So after we've run a sequence of requests
在我们运行一系列请求之后
The aggregate payload is the sum of all the the payloads in the currently allocated blocks
聚合有效载荷是当前分配的块中所有有效载荷的总和
So in a perfect allocator
在完美的分配器中
The aggregate payload would equal the amount of memory
聚合有效负载等于内存量
The total size of all the allocated blocks right because there'd be no overhead
等于所有已分配块的总大小，因为没有开销
We just be pure every block would be pure payload
每个块都是有效载荷
Now we're going to assume that the heap is monotonically non-decreasing so it always gets bigger
现在我们假设堆是单调非递减的，所以它总是变大
Okay so are this is a simplifying assumption,it's not true in a real malloc package
这是一个简化的假设，在真正的 malloc 包中不是这样
But we'll just assume that the allocator never decreases the size of the heap
我们假设分配器永远不会减小堆的大小
It only increases the size of the heap okay
它只会增加堆的大小
So the peak given those notions of aggregate payload and heap size
所以峰值给出了聚合有效载荷和堆大小的概念
The peak memory utilization after k+1 requests
k + 1 个请求后的峰值内存利用率
It's the sum of all the payloads divided by the total size of the heap
它是所有有效负载的总和除以堆的总大小
So the in the best case
所以在最好的情况下
Each block in the heap consists of pure payload
堆中的每个块的内容都是有效负载
So the utilization would be 1
因此利用率为 1
That's the best we can do
这是我们能做的最好的事情
But in practice each block the allocator is going to place have data structures and padding inside of each block
但实际上，在分配器将要放置的每个块的内部，都有数据结构和其他内容
That keep it from getting a perfect utilization
这使它无法获得完美的利用率
Now one obvious thing is that since blocks have to be aligned
一个显而易见的事情是，因为块必须对齐
To some you know if they're 16-byte aligned then blocks have to start on 16 byte boundaries
如果它们是 16 字节对齐的，那么块必须以 16 字节边界开始
And they have to be at least 16 bytes
它们必须至少为 16 个字节
So if you were to request a payload of 2 bytes
因此，如果你要请求 2 字节的有效负载
You'd have a lot of wasted bytes right that would sort of decrease the utilization
你有很多浪费的字节，这会降低利用率
So this is some of this some of this overhead is unavoidable
所以这是其中一些开销是不可避免的
But your job as a someone who writes them implements malloc is to try to keep that as small as possible
但是你作为一个编写实现 malloc 人，你的的工作就是尽量使得这些浪费减小
So poor memory utilization is this example that we just talked about is an example of what we call fragmentation
因此，我们刚才谈到的这个例子就是我们称之为 「碎片」 的一个例子
And there's two types of fragmentation
而且有两种类型的碎片
Internal fragmentation occurs if the payload is smaller than the block size
如果有效负载小于块大小，则会发生内部碎片
So it's just what we're talking about
所以这正是我们所谈论的
And this can be caused by either padding in the block or some kind of data structure in the block that the allocator needs
这可能是由块中的填充或分配器需要的块中的某种数据结构引起的
Sometimes to it you might make a policy decision
有时，你可能会做出一个策略决定
That if application requests a small block you might return a larger block just to keep
如果应用程序请求一个小块，你可能会返回一个更大的块来保持
So the blocks don't get sort of splintered up into little chunks you might want to keep blocks at some minimum size
因此，这些块不会分裂成小块，你可能希望将块保持在某个最小尺寸
Now internal fragmentation. You know given a series of requests
现在来谈论一下内部碎片。一系列给给予的请求
We can just stop and freeze the heap
我们可以停止并冻结堆
And it's very easy to sort of compute the amount of internal fragmentation
并且计算内部碎片的数量非常容易
We can at any point in time we can just look at all the previous requests that we've made
在任何时候我们都可以查看我们之前提出的所有要求
And look at the size of the payload for each one of those requests
并查看每个请求的有效负载大小
And so we can
所以我们可以
So we can determine the level you know get at a point in time,we can determine the level of internal fragmentation
因此，我们可以在某个时间点确定内部碎片的级别
Just by looking at the previous request
只需查看之前的请求即可
So
所以
There's another form of fragmentation called external fragmentation which is a little more difficult to deal with
还有另一种形式的碎片称为 「外部碎片」，这种碎片更难处理
So external fragmentation occurs when there's enough memory in the heap
外部碎片发生在堆中有足够的内存时
But there's no single free block that can satisfy a particular request
但是没有一个可以满足特定请求的空闲块
Ok so external fragmentation occurs when the application makes a request for a block
所以外部碎片发生在当应用程序发出块请求时
But nowhere in the heap is a free block that's large enough to satisfy that request
但堆中没有一个足够大的空闲块来满足该请求
So an example of this like suppose
所以这个例子就像假设一样
Here's the previous example we looked at
这是我们上面看到的前一个例子
Now where we have after a series of malloc and free calls
现在我们在一系列 malloc 和 free 调用之后
We have two free blocks in the heap
我们在堆中有两个空闲块
One containing 5 words and the other containing 2 words
一个包含 5 个字，另一个包含 2 个字
So the total number of free words in our heap is 7 words
所以我们堆中的空闲的字总数是 7 个字
And now we get a request for 6 words
现在我们收到 6 个字的请求
Hey we have enough free blocks, we have enough free words in the heap
嘿，我们有足够的空闲块，我们在堆中有足够的空间
But we can't satisfy that request
但我们无法满足这一要求
And it's because of this phenomenon called external fragmentation
这是因为外部碎片这种现象
For example if we'd have somehow allocated
例如，如果我们以某种方式分配
Oh
哦
Yeah I don't know in this case I don't think we could have avoided the external fragmentation
我认为我们不能避免外部碎片
But nonetheless there's enough memory here. We just the way that a blocks are configured in the heap
但是，无庸置疑这里由足够的内存。我们配置堆中块的方式
We can't satisfy the request
无法满足请求
So in this case that the allocator has to go and get more virtual memory
所以在这种情况下，分配器必须去获得更多的虚拟内存
It would have to get more virtual memory and extend the heap out this way
它必须获得更多虚拟内存，并在堆的这后面进行扩展
And to get a large enough free block
并获得足够大的免空闲块
So you know assessing and sort of understanding external fragmentation is difficult
因此，评估和理解外部碎片很困难
Because unlike internal fragmentation which depended on the previous requests
因为不同于内部碎片，这取决于之前的要求
External fragmentation depends on future requests
外部碎片取决于未来的要求
So if we look back at this point
所以，如果我们回顾这一点
We see is a heap externally fragmented
我们看到的是外部碎片堆
Well we it depends right. we can't say ...
这取决于 … 我们不能说 …
It turns out it is because the next request is for a block of size six
这是因为下一个请求是针对大小为 6 的块
But if all of the future blocks
但如果所有的未来块
Or future requests we're for blocks of you know say small blocks
或者未来我们对于小块的请求
Then we be able to satisfy those than and we wouldn't suffer from external fragmentation
那我们能够满足那些请求，而且我们不会受到外部碎片的影响
Okay now when we build an allocated
好的，现在我们建立一个分配的
All kinds of issues come up
出现了各种各样的问题
And that I've glossed over with my simple examples right
我用简单的例子对我进行了解释
You know how do we know
我们怎么知道
If we call free,how does free know how much memory to free up
如果我们调用了 free，free 如何知道要释放多少内存
Right we don't call free with a block size we call it with a pointer
我们不用块大小调用 free，我们用指针调用它
So how does free know how big that block is
free 如何知道该块有多大
How do we keep track of all the free blocks
我们如何跟踪所有空闲块
When we have you know when we're satisfying an allocation request
当满足分配请求时
We're going to fight we're going to look for a free block
我们将寻找一个空闲块
That is larger than the requested size
这个块大于请求的大小
On that case what do we do with the extra space in the block
在那种情况下，我们如何处理块中的额外空间
We do we just keep it in the block
我们只是将它保留在块中
You know and and suffer some internal fragmentation
遭受一些内部碎片化
Do we split that block into a smaller block
我们是否将该块拆分为较小的块
There's a lot of free blocks in the heap
堆中有很多空闲块
When the allocator gets a allocation request
当分配器获得分配请求时
How does it pick from all of those different free blocks make as many choices
如何选择这些不同的空闲块
And then once when free tries to insert a free block we're in the heap
当 free 尝试插入一个空闲块时，在堆中
You know where does it insert
它在哪里插入
It okay when it's freed
当它被释放时
And how do we reinsert a free block what does that mean
我们如何重新插入一个空闲块，这意味着什么
Okay so today we're going to look at all of these issues
今天我们要看看所有这些问题
Starting with knowing how much to free
从知道要释放多少开始
So how big our block sizes
那么我们的块大小有多大
So the typical the standard method
典型的标准方法
Is to keep sort of a word sized quantity at the beginning of each block
是在每个块的开头使用一个字大小的的区域
That gives the size of that block in some units
它记录了某些单元中该块的大小
I'm showing them here in word size units
我在这里用字大小单位显示它们
Okay so that if the application malloc a payload of size wants to malloc a payload of size 4
如果应用程序想要 malloc 一个大小为 4 字的负载荷
Then the allocator needs to find a block of size 5
分配器需要找到大小为 5 的块
So consisting of 4 payload words at least 4 payload words
因此，由 4 个有效载荷字组成，至少 4 个有效载荷字
And then a header block,a header word at the beginning that indicates the size,the total size of that block
头部字表示该块的总大小
And then it returns a pointer p0 in this case to the beginning of the payload
在这种情况下它将返回指向有效负载荷开头指针 p0
Okay so now we know how big each block is that's pretty simple
现在我们知道每个块有多大，这很简单
And how we keep track of the free blocks and this is where it gets interesting
那以及我们如何跟踪空闲块，这就是它变得有趣的地方
The simplest method is to use that we call an implicit list
最简单的方法是使用我们称为隐式列表的方法
An implicit list of free blocks
一个隐式的空闲块列表
And the idea here is to just put a header in the front of every block in the heap
它的思想是在堆中的每个块的前面放置一个头部
Whether allocated or free
无论是被分配了还是空闲的
And then we can use that starting at the beginning of the heap, we can use that size to walk the heap
然后我们可以在堆的开头使用它，我们可以使用头部记录的大小来访问堆
Okay so here's a block of size 5 so we can we can jump
所以这是一个 5 个字大小的块，所以我们可以跳
We know that the next block starts at an offset of 5
我们知道下一个块的偏移量为 5
With the second block we know the next block starts at an offset of 4  and so on
对于第二个块，我们知道下一个块的偏移量为 4，依此类推
Okay so we call it an implicit free list
我们称之为隐式空闲列表
Because there's no real list of free blocks
因为没有真正的空闲块列表
But we can trick an traverse that all of the free blocks in the heap
但是我们可以巧妙地遍历堆中的所有空闲块
By traversing all of the blocks in the heap
通过在堆中遍历所有块
And then just ignoring the allocated blocks okay so
只是忽略已分配的块就可以了
Now another thing we could do is
现在我们可以做的另一件事是
We could actually use some of the words in the block
我们实际上可以使用块中的一些字
To create a linked list of some kind either us
去创建某种链接列表
Singly or doubly linked lists
单链或双链表
And in this case it's an explicit list of the free blocks
在这种情况下，这是一个明确的空闲块列表
And we can just walk that list
我们可以访问这个列表
So we here we visit the first free block
我们在这里访问第一个空闲区块
And then there's a pointer to the next free block and so on
然后有一个指向下一个空闲块的指针，依此类推
So this you can see this might be a little more efficient because
所以你可以看到这可能会更高效，因为
If we want to traverse the free list
如果我们想要遍历空闲列表
In this case it's going to be ordered the number of blocks in the list
在这种情况下，将按顺序排列列表中的块数
Okay it's going to be linear in the total number of blocks in the heap
它将与堆中的块总数中呈线性
Which might be quite large there could be lots of allocated blocks
这个列表可能很大，因为可能会有很多已分配的块
In this case with an explicit list
在这种情况下有一个明确的列表
Any traversal just just be linear in the size of the free list
任何遍历与空闲列表的大小线性相关
Question
学生提问
[student speaking]
Yeah that's the question is done we need a free bit and we do
是的，问题已经解决了，我们需要一个空闲的位，我们也是这么做的
And I'll we have that's the next question
我接下来会问这个问题
Now another method a more sophisticated method instead of having one free list
现在另一种方法是一种更复杂的方法，而不是一个空闲列表
We can have multiple free lists
我们可以有多个空闲列表
Where each free list contains blocks of a certain size or certain range of sizes
每个空闲列表包含特定大小或特定大小范围的块
Or we can get really fancy and use some kind of a balance tree
或者我们可以非常喜欢使用某种平衡树
To sort the blocks to use the tree to sort them by size order
使用树将块按照大小来排序
Now today we're going to look at the implicit list
今天我们要看看隐式列表
The simplest kind of free list
最简单的空闲列表
And this will identify a lot of basic concepts that are used in the more sophisticated free list
这里将定义许多更复杂的在空闲列表中使用的基本概念
Question
学生提问
[student speaking]
Okay the question is what do you what do we mean by different free lists for different size classes
好的问题是，对于不同大小的块有不同的空闲列表是什么意思？
So what I mean is that you identify a range of sizes
我的意思是你确定了一系列尺寸
And you associate that range with each of these individual free lists
并且你将该范围与每个单独的空闲列表相关联
Okay so one free list might hold blocks of size 0 to 8
好的，所以一个空闲列表可能包含 0 到 8 字大小的块
And another free list might hold blocks of size 9 to 16
另一个空闲列表可能包含大小为 9 到 16 字大小的块
And the other another free list may be 17 to 32 you know some
而另一个空闲列表可能是 17 到 32 字的块
And so you're guaranteed you now know
所以这保证了你现在知道了
When you're traversing a certain list you know the range of sizes of the blocks in that list
当你遍历某个列表时，你知道该列表中块的大小范围
The reason you might want to do that
你可能想要这样做的原因
By the way is that imagine you had an infinite number of these lists
顺便说一句，想象一下，你有无数的这些列表
One for each possible size
每个列表对应一个大小
Then every time you allocated a block
然后每次你分配一个块
You'd get a block of exactly the size you needed
你会得到一个与你需要的尺寸完全相同的块
So there'd be a minimum amount of fragmentation if you had an infinite number of these size classes
因此，如果各个不同大小的块都有很多个，会有最少的碎片
Now if we of course we can't have an infinite number but
我们当然不能拥有无限个，但是
The more of these size classes we have the closer we get to that ideal
这些尺寸大小的类别越多，我们越接近理想的情况
All right so let's look at how we would build implicit free lists
好的，让我们来看看如何构建隐式空闲列表
So as you correctly point it out for each
你可以看出
Each block we need both size and the allocation status
每个块我们都需要大小和分配状态
Question
学生提问
[student speaking]
Why can't we map every size class
我们为什么不能映射每个大小的类
[student speaking]
Yeah that's so why can't we have an infinite number of size classes
是的，为什么我们不能拥有无限数量的不同大小的类
I suppose you know that'd be an interesting strategy to think about
这是一个值得思考的有趣策略
So you can't have an infinite number of size classes
你不能拥有无限数量的大小类
But you could create a new size class for every new size that you get
但是你可以为你得到的每个新尺寸创建一个新的尺寸类
And that might work but it just depends on the range of these size classes
这可能会奏效，但这取决于这些大小类的范围
And the frequency and one problem you might have is that you would get
你可能会遇一些问题
Maybe it depends on the distribution of your sizes that you get
也许它取决于你得到的尺寸分布
If you're getting an equal number, if your distribution of sizes is fairly uniform
如果你得到一个相同的数字，如果你的尺寸分布相当均匀
That would probably work pretty well
这可能会很好
If you have a lot of requests for different size classes,you'd have a lot of sort of wasted free lists I think
如果你对很多不同大小的类请求，我认为你会有很多浪费的空闲列表
So it's a good question,it depends on your workload
所以这是一个很好的问题，这取决于你的工作量
And  that is a really useful strategy for
这是一个非常有用的策略
So you if you have really popular size classes in your request
如果你在请求中有非常常用的大小类
Then you could just make you know special case free lists to handle those requests
然后你可以让特殊情况下的空闲列表来处理这些请求
And then let the other free list sort of handle a wider range
然后让其他空闲列表处理更广的范围
And imagine if you had a free list where all the blocks were the same
想象一下，如果你有一个空闲列表，其中所有块都是相同的
It could be a lot more efficient right because
它可能效率更高，因为
You only need like a bit vector
你只需要一点矢量
1 bit for each potential block to tell you whether it's allocated or free
每个潜在块只需要 1 位就能确定它是已分配的还是空闲
So it could be very efficient you wouldn't need to walk any lists or anything
所以这是非常高效，你不需要去遍历任何列表
That's a good question and that's the kind of thing you'll be thinking about when you do your malloc lab
这是一个很好的问题，这是你在做 malloc 实验时会想到的事情
The there's a huge design space in implementing malloc function
实现 malloc 功能有一个巨大的设计空间
And we just explored a one tiny part of it just now
我们刚刚探讨了它的一小部分
So with this implicit list we're going to need both the size of the block
因此，使用这个隐式列表，我们将需要块的大小
And then its allocation status whether it's allocated or free
也需要它的分配状态 —— 块是已分配还是空闲的
Now we could do this in 2 words right but that would be wasteful
现在我们可以用 2 个字来做到这一点，但那将是浪费
So the standard trick is to take advantage of the fact that blocks have to be aligned
因此，标准技巧是利用块必须对齐的事实
Okay so this is actually it's kind of a pain in the neck to always have to align these blocks
总是必须对齐这些块实际上是痛苦的瓶颈
But we can take advantage of it in this case
但在这种情况下我们可以利用它
And the reason is that if a block is aligned to some say 8 byte or 16 byte boundary
原因是如果一个块与 8 字节或 16 字节边界对齐
Then the lower order bits are always going to be 0
然后低位总是为 0
So if it's aligned to an 8 byte boundary
因此，如果它与 8 字节边界对齐
The 3 low order bits will always be 0
低 3 位始终为 0
Right 8 is 1000
8 是 1000
16 (=) 10000
24 (=) 11000
Right so there any 8 byte
所以任何 8 字节
Any 8 byte aligned block has to be size 8 and it has to start on address that's a multiple of 8 all right
任何 8 字节对齐的块必须是大小为 8，它的地址必须是 8 的倍数
So the size of that block will always have
所以这些块的大小一直有
3 or 4 a low-order bits set to 0
3 或 4 个低位设置为 0
So we can take advantage of that
所以我们可以利用这一点
And we will just have 1 header word
我们只需要一个字大小的头部
And we'll use the lower order bit to store the allocation status
我们将使用低位来存储分配状态
Okay and we can do that because we know it's always zero
好的，我们可以做到这一点，因为我们知道它始终为零
So we use that low order bit to store the allocation status
因此，我们使用该低位来存储分配状态
And then the remaining bits correspond to the size
然后剩余的位对应于大小
And then whenever we want to extract the size we just mask out this allocation status and always set it to zero
然后，只要我们想要提取大小，我们就会掩饰掉这个分配状态并始终将其设置为零
Because we know that it's zero
因为我们知道它是零
So let's look in detail what given this form of implicit list
让我们详细了解一下这种隐式列表的形式
How we might set things up
我们如何设置
So in this case we're going to assume for byte words okay in sized words
因此，在这种情况下，我们将假设字节大小可以用字来表示
And we're going to align on 8 byte boundaries
我们将在 8 字节边界上对齐
Okay so remember the payload of a blocks always has to start on an 8 byte boundary
好的，记住块的有效负载总是必须从 8 字节边界开始
So the way we do that is we create this unused word at the beginning of the heap
所以我们这样做的方法是在堆的开头创建这个未使用的字
That's aligned on this 8 byte boundary
它在 8 字节边界上对齐
And then the first block and the heap starts at an offset of 4 from the beginning of the heap
然后第一个块从堆的开头偏移 4 开始
So we have the header which is is not aligned
所以头部没有对齐
And then we have the payload which follows
然后接下来的部分有了有效负载荷
In this case it's a payload of one word and that starts on this
在这种情况下，它是一个字大小的有效负载
That begins on this 8 word boundary
它从这个 8 字大小的边界开始
And then the next block and and here we're indicating a free block consisting of 8 bytes
然后是下一个块，一个由 8 个字节组成的空闲块
And then that's followed by an allocated block
然后是一个已分配的块
The one here of 16 bytes or 4 words
这里的一个是 16 字节或者说 4 个字
And now the payload is only 2 words so we have to pad right all of a block
现在有效载荷只有 2 个字，所以我们必须填充块的所有其他部分
Because we're assuming that they're aligned on 8 byte boundary
因为我们假设它们在 8 字节对齐
All of a blocks have to be a multiple of size multiple of 8
所有块的大小必须是 8 的倍数
Okay so here's the case of internal fragmentation where we have this extra
好的，所以这里是内部碎片的情况
This extra block in order to maintain the alignment requirement
这种情况中额外的块是为了保持对齐要求
So that ensures that the next block payload starts at an 8 byte aligned boundary and so on
这样可以确保下一个块有效负载从 8 字节对齐的边界开始，依此类推
And so we can walk this heap by just following these headers masking out the allocation bits
因此，我们可以使用掩码，从头部中获得分配信息位，然后可以通过头部来遍历此堆
And then we have this special epilogue block
然后我们有这个特殊的结局块
Which is a zero,it's a block of with a zero sized payload
这是一个零，它是一个零大小的有效载荷块
It's an allocated block of size 0
它是一个大小为 0 的已分配块
And this is a trick
这是一个技巧
This is a trick you should use to
这是你应该使用的技巧
So this and we'll see when we look at coalescing why this helps
当我们考虑合并时我们会知道为什么这会有所帮助
But this allocated block at the very end
但是这个分配的块在最后
Eliminates some sort of special cases when we start to coalesce free blocks
当我们开始合并空闲块时，消除某种特殊情况
We'll talk about that in just a just a moment
我们等下将讨论这个问题
But you can finish your
但你可以完成你的搜索时
This allocated block of size zero is also helpful in terminating
这个已分配的大小为零的块也有助于终止访问
When you're walking this list
当你遍历这个名单时
You can check for a size allocated block of size zero to terminate your search
你可以检查大小为零的块大小以终止搜索
Okay so given this kind of structure then how do we find a free block
好吧，鉴于这种结构，我们如何找到一个空闲块
Okay there's a number of different ways
好吧，有很多不同的方式
The first way which is called first fit is to search the free list from the beginning
第一种称为 「首次适配」 的方法是从头开始搜索空闲列表
And just look for the first block we can find that satisfies the request
只需查找我们可以找到满足请求的第一个块
So we're allocating we're asking for a block of size 10
所以我们要分配的块大小为 10
We start at the beginning of the heap and we walked a list we walk the heap
我们从堆的开头开始，然后我们遍历一个列表
Looking for a free block that's at least size 10
寻找一个至少 10 字大小的空闲块
And we needs to be actually it needs to be 10 plus the size of our header 2
而且我们需要实际上需要 10 加上头部大小 2 的总大小
So that's a simple idea now
所以现在这是一个简单的想法
Some people have proposed an alternative called next fit
有些人提出了一种称为 「下一次适配」 的替代品
So the idea here is that instead of starting over each time from the beginning of the heap to find a block that fits
其的想法是，不是从堆的开头每次开始去找到适合的块
We just pick up where we left off the last time
我们从最后一次离开的地方开始
Okay so we look,we scan the heap
我们扫描堆
And we find a block that's big enough to satisfy the request
我们找到一个足以满足请求的块
And then we remember where we left off
然后我们记住我们离开的地方
And the next time the request comes in we pick up the search starting where we left off
下次响应请求时，我们从上次离开的地方开始搜索
Now this seems like would be a good idea but peer studies that people have done
现在这似乎是一个好主意，但人们所做的研究
Have shown that this actually results in worse fragmentation
已经证明这实际上会导致更糟糕的碎片
So you know you can consider it but it generally
所以你可以考虑它
It's generally probably not the best thing to do
这通常可能不是最好的方法
Now another alternative is to find a free block in the heap that's the best fit
现在另一种方法是在堆中找到最佳适配的块
So in general look at all the blocks in the heap and find the block that fits the best
所以一般查看堆中的所有块，找到最佳适配的块
If we ask for 10 bytes
如果我们要求 10 个字节
Try to scan the heap for the block that has the closest to 10 bytes in it
尝试扫描堆中最接近 10 个字节的块
Okay so that's called best fit
所以这被称为 「最佳适配」
And best fit you can see it might be more it sounds like it would be a lot more expensive right
最佳适配可能看起来会带来更大的消耗
Because you'd have to look instead of just looking until you find a fit
因为在你找到合适的东西之前，你必须一直寻找
You'd have to scan all the free blocks and then pick the best one
你必须扫描所有空闲块，然后选择最好的区块
Okay but it has a nice property that it improves memory utilization
但它有一个很好的属性，它提高了内存利用率
Okay so this is a classic example the space time trade-off
这是一个典型时空权衡的例子
So it's slower but it improves a use of the efficiency of the way we use memory
它的速度较慢，但​​它提高了我们使用内存的效率
And there's
还有
Now we mentioned an alternative way to organize the free list using multiple free lists for different size classes
现在我们提到了一种使用多个不同大小类的空闲列表来组织空闲列表的替代方法
Now going back to that example again if we had an infinite number of size classes
我们回到之前的例子，如果我们有无限数量的各个大小的类
One for each size that would implement best fit
每种类对应一种大小，它们都可以实现最佳配合适配
With a constant time search we'd know exactly which free list to get the block from
通过一定的时间的搜索，我们可以确切地知道从哪个空闲列表中获取块
The problem of course is how much memory such a organization would use
问题是这样一个组织会使用多少内存
But the interesting thing about using multiple free lists
关于使用多个空闲列表有趣的点是
Is that the more of these free lists you have the closer you get to it to a true best fit
你拥有的这些空闲列表越多，就越接近真正的最佳状态
Okay so you can approach best fit
好的，你可以接近最佳适配
And then at some point you begin to get diminishing returns
然后在某些时候你会开始收益递减
So that's another sort of design decision is how many of these multiple free lists do you need and what
因此，另一种设计决策是你需要多少个空闲列表
What's sort of what should be the size ranges associated with them
以及它们所关联的块的大小的范围是多少
Okay another question now once we found a block
另一个问题是，一旦我们找了一个块
So the application is made a call to malloc
应用程序调用 malloc
The malloc package is look in the free list that somehow using some
malloc 包访问一些的空闲列表
Some policy it's identified a block that
使用一些政策以确定了一个块
In which the requested block a free block in which the requested block will fit
这个块是空闲的，并且适配所请求的块
Okay so now what does it do, the malloc package has to allocate
现在它做了什么，malloc 包必须去分配
It has to sort of take that
它必须采取这种方式
So there's a question how does...it could allocate the whole block
但是有一个问题是它如何分配整个块
And return that back to the programmer or it could choose to split out
然后将其返回给程序员，或者选择拆分
Just only the portion of block that's needed and then create a smaller free block
只是块所需的一部分，然后创建一个较小的空闲块
Okay so for example if we...
好的，例如，如果我们......
If our application is has requested a block of size 4
如果我们的应用程序请求大小为 4 的块
Or I'm sorry
我很抱歉
If the malloc package is determined that it in order to satisfy the application request
如果 malloc 包确定它需要满足应用程序的请求
It needs a block of size 4
它需要一个大小为 4 的块
Okay including the header
包括头部
Then it would try to find a free block of at least size 4
然后它会尝试找到大小至少为 4 的块
So let's say it chooses this block for some reason
所以我们说它出于某种原因选择了这个块
Maybe because it was a next fit picked up here
也许是因为这是下一次适配
So this free block is actually six
所以这个空闲块的大小实际上是 6
Contains six words
包含六个字
So the allocator has to decide whether just to keep this block of size 6
所以分配器必须决定是否只保留这个大小为 6 的块
And just return that back to the application
然后将其返回给应用程序
Or whether to split that block into 2 blocks into an allocated block of size 4
或者是否将该块分成 2 个块，分成一个大小为 4 的已分配的块
Which it then returns to the application followed by a free block of of size 2
然后返回到应用程序，其后面是大小为 2 的空闲块
Okay now another question is how to free a block
现在另一个问题是如何释放一个块
So the application calls free and it's asked the allocator to free up a particular block
应用程序调用来 free， 它要求分配器去释放一个特定的块
So this is pretty simple
所以这很简单
So if we want to free up this block you just clear the allocated flag
如果我们要释放此块，你只需清除已分配的标志即可
So if we want to free up the block we just created
所以，如果我们想要释放我们刚创建的块
You just set the allocated bit to zero
你只需将分配的位设置为零即可
And you're done, it's really simple
你已经完成了，它非常简单
But the problem now is this creates external fragmentation
但现在的问题是这会造成外部碎片化
So here now if we just free that block of size 4
所以现在，如果我们只是释放大小为 4 的块
What used to be a block of size 6
它曾经是大小为 6 的块
Now consists of 2 contiguous smaller blocks one of size 4 and one of size 2
现在由 2 个连续的较小块组成，其中一个大小为 4，其中一个大小为 2
And so now if that's followed by a request for 5 blocks
所以现在如果之后是5块的请求
Now we're stuck right so this
现在我们被困住了
But we've got plenty of memory and it's even worse in this case
但是我们有足够的内存，在这种情况下甚至更糟
That memory is all contiguous just because
内存是完全连续的
But just because we just oh we just cleared the free block
但仅仅因为我们只是清除了空闲块
We didn't really notice that it was contiguous
我们并没有真正注意到它是连续的
And so we ended up in with the situation where we have these two contiguous free blocks
因此我们最终得到了两个连续的空闲块的情况
So this suggests that
所以这表明了
When we free up blocks
当我们释放块时
That we somehow need to coalesce any neighboring blocks
我们需要合并任何相邻的块
To keep blocks as big as possible right so we cannot
尽以量保持块尽可能大
One of the invariance of any decent allocator is that
任何优秀的分配器的不变性之一就是
They're never contiguous free blocks like this
它们永远不会使得多个连续的空闲块存在
It's always a free block followed by an allocated block
它始终是一个空闲块后跟一个已分配的块
Okay so the idea is that if we free a particular so here we have this allocated block
所以我的想法是，如果我们释放一个特定的已分配的块
And if we free that block and we somehow have to check
如果我们释放该块，我们必须检查
And see if there's any adjacent free blocks either following
查看是否存在任何相邻的空闲块
Either next in memory or previous in memory
这个空闲块可能是下一个内存块或前一个内存块
And if there are we need to as part of the freeing process
作为解放过程的一部分
We need to coalesce those 2 blocks into a into the largest possible block possible
我们需要将这两个块合并为一个尽可能最大的块
Now it's pretty easy if we're asked to free this block this green block
如果我们被要求释放这个绿色区块
It's pretty easy to check the next block because you just
可以很容易地检查下一个区块
We have the size we have this header
我们有头部记录了这个块的大小
So we know that the next block starts at an offset of 4
所以我们知道下一个块的偏移量为 4
So we just check
所以我们只是检查
And we know that the header for that block is at offset of 4
我们知道该块的头部位于你的偏移量 4 处
So we just check the allocated status of that next block using the
所以我们需要检查下一个块的分配状态
Using the size field in our header
使用头部中的 size 字段
But what about the previous block
但是前一个块呢
What about this block how do we check that
我们如何检测那个块
Well given all that we've talked about
考虑到我们所谈论的所有内容
Now the only thing,the only way we could do it would be to start at the beginning of the heap
现在唯一的事情，我们能做到的唯一方法就是从堆的开头开始
And now walk the free list until we get to this current block remembering the previous block
遍历空闲列表，直到我们到达当前块记住前一个块
So each time we traverse we remember the previous block
因此，每次我们遍历时，我们都会记住上一个块
Okay so that would be very inefficient right
好的，所以这样效率非常低
That would make free linear in the size of the heap
这会使得 free 的过程与堆的大小呈线形的关系
Because we'd have to in order to check the previous block we'd have to walk starting at the very beginning
因为我们必须要检查前一个区块，所以我们必须从头开始遍历
And walk the entire heap
遍历整个堆
So the solution for that is was proposed by a famous computer scientist Don Knuth in 1973
对于这个问题的解决方案是由着名计算机科学家 Don Knuth 在 1973 年提出的
It's very clever,it very simple like all really good ideas
它非常聪明，非常简单，就像所有非常好的想法一样
It seems obvious that when you see it but it turns out to be very clever and a very useful technique
很明显，事实证明它非常聪明并且是一种非常有用的技术
And the idea is just to replicate for each block
而这个想法只是
Replicate the header block at the end of the block
将块的头部复制到块的脚部
Okay so each block now contains a header and a footer identical header and footer
好的，所以每个块现在包含一个头部和一个相同的脚部
And then this creates sort of an implicit backwards
然后这会产生一种隐含的回溯
Backwards link that we can use
我们可以使用的向后链接
So now given some block
所以现在给出一些块
Given some block that we want to free
给出一些我们想要释放的块
We knew the size of that block will just be one word previous in memory so
我们知道这个块的大小只是内存中的一个字
So it's always a fixed offset of one word
它始终是一个字大小的固定偏移量
So given you know given a pointer to the header of this block
所以给出一个指向这个块的头部的指针
We can look one word back to see the size and the allocation status of the previous block
我们可以回过头来查看前一个块的大小和分配状态
Okay so and so that allows us to do that in constant time
好吧，这样我们就可以在常数的时间内做到这一点
And so this footer is sometimes called the boundary tag  and Knuth call that a boundary tag
所以这个脚部有时被称为边界标记，而 Knuth 称之为边界标记
But we can call it a footer to be sort of parallel with the notion of a header
但我们可以把它称为脚部，与头部的概念并行
But the key thing is that it's just identical has the identical size and allocation status
但关键是它完全相同，具有相同的大小和分配状态
Question
学生提问
[student speaking]
So the question is if we want to have a boundary tag
所以问题是我们是否想要一个边界标签
When we allocate a block do we need to set aside space for it and the answer is yes
当我们分配一个块时，我们需要为它留出空间吗？答案是肯定的
Most of the time I'll show you one optimization in a bit
我会稍微向你展示一个优化
Okay so given this idea of a over the boundary tag
所以给出了一个跨越边界标签的想法
And given that we have some allocated block that we want to free
这里有一些有一些我们想要释放的分配块
This yellow block
这个黄色块
Yes question
学生提问
[student speaking]
So just to summarize the question
总结一下这个问题
When you're looking for blocks that fit
当你正在寻找适合的块时
You have to include the the size of the header and the boundary tag
你必须包括头部的大小和边界标记
[student speaking]
Then you'd have to insert padding to get a total block size
那么你需要插入填充以获得总块的大小
That's a multiple that satisfies your alignment requirement
这是满足你的字节对齐的要求
Sorry
抱歉
Yeah I mean it can yeah
是的我的意思是它可以
The question is wouldn't I use a lot of memory and it can again it depends on the requests
问题是这是否会使用大量内存，它可以取决于请求
The request pattern if the application is requesting lots of small payloads then
请求模式，如果应用程序正在请求大量的小有效负载
Then it's going to waste a lot of memory
然后它会浪费大量的内存
If it's requesting big payloads not so bad
如果它要求大的有效载荷不是那么糟糕
Okay so given that we have some block that we want to free
我们有一些我们想要释放的块
There's 4 cases that we need to consider when coalescing
合并时我们需要考虑 4 种情况
The case where the next block is allocated and the previous block is free is allocated
下一个块被分配，前一个块也被分配的情况
A case where the next block is free and the previous block is allocated
下一个块空闲且前一个块被分配的情况
A case where the previous block is free
前一个块是空闲
And the next block is allocated in the case where both the previous and next block are free
但后一个块被分配了，前后两个块都是空闲的情况
Okay so in case one where we have an allocated block
在情况一中，我们有一个想要被释放的被分配的块
That we want to free surrounded by two allocated blocks
它被两个被分配的块包围
We don't do anything right because we only call us free memory
我们没有做任何事情，因为我们只需要调用 free
So so in this case we just set keep the size of the header and footer stays the same
所以在这种情况下我们只是保持页眉和页脚的大小保持不变
And we just set the allocation status to shift free
我们只是将分配状态设置为空闲
Now if the next block is free and the previous block is allocated
如果下一个块是空闲的，而分配前一个块
What we do is we check the boundary tag of the previous block
我们要做的是检查前一个块的边界标记
And we see that it's allocated so there's nothing to do there
我们看到它被分配，所以没有什么可做的
We use the size to check the allocation status of the next block
我们使用大小来检查下一个块的分配状态
We use n to jump to the header of the next block
我们使用 n 跳转到下一个块的头部
We see that it's allocations status is free
我们看到它的分配状态是空闲的
So these two blocks need to be coalesced
所以这两个块需要合并
So we do that by just adding the two sizes together to create this larger coalesce block
所以我们只需将两个大小相加就可以创建更大的合并块
And setting its allocation status to zero
并将其分配状态设置为零
Now in the case where the previous block is free
现在，前一个块是空闲的
Again we check the boundary tech footer when we see that it's we see it it's free
当我们看到它是空闲的时候，我们再次检查脚部
So in this case we create
所以在这种情况下
We have to update the size
我们必须更新大小
The header of the old previous block to create this now new larger coalesce block
旧的前一个块的头部创建了这个新的更大的合并块
And we update the header and the boundary check footer accordingly
我们相应地更新头部和边界脚步
And then in the case where both the previous
然后在这种情况下
And the next block are free
前一个和后一个块都是空闲的
We create a single block
我们创建一个块
A single block that's the sum of all 3 of those sizes
这个单个块是3个大小的总和
Okay so is that ,is that clear to everybody?
好的，那对每个人都清楚吗？
Now as you pointed out correctly pointed out that
正如正确地指出的
Boundary tags can create additional internal fragmentation
边界标记可以造成额外的内部碎片
Because they're not part of payload so by definition
因为根据定义它们不是有效载荷的一部分
They're overhead
它们是开销
And so you might ask yourself are there any cases where
所以你可能会问自己
You don't need a boundary tag
是否有某一种情况不需要边界标记
So which blocks need
那么哪些块需要
Which blocks need a boundary tag
哪些块需要边界标记
Could you get away with does an allocated block need one?
分配的块不需要吗？
[student speaking]
Yeah if you don't need to coalesce
是的，如果你不需要合并
And you don't need to that footer and what kind of blocks don't you coalesce
而且你不需要那个脚部，什么块不需要合并呢？
Allocated blocks
已分配的块
So what
所以呢
So maybe we don't need those at those boundary tech footers on allocated blocks
所以也许在那些已分配的快上我们不需要边界标记技术
Right just on free blocks
只在空闲块上需要
But then how are we going to determine that the previous block is allocated or free
但那么我们如何确定前一个块是已分配还是空闲的
If an allocated block doesn't have a boundary tag footer
如果已分配的块没有边界标记页脚脚部
Yes
是
[student speaking]
Well yeah you would give it one when you free it
是的，当你释放它时，你会给它一个
But somehow when we're doing coalescing we need to check somehow that previous block
但当我们进行合并时，我们需要以某种方式检查前一个块
Whether it's allocated or free okay
无论是分配还是空闲的
But how does it know it's whether it's a boundary tag
但它是如何知道它是否是边界标签
Or not sure no that's okay
或者不确定。没关系
Okay yes
好的，是的
Bingo you got it.So remember this remember because of our alignment
对了，你懂了。所以记住这一点，因为字节对齐
We've got multiple at least three bits in three or four bits that are always zero
至少有三位或者四位总是 0
We're only using one of them
我们只使用其中一个
So why not use another one to contain the allocation status of the previous block
那么为什么不使用另一个来包含前一个块的分配状态
Okay so very good that was
好的，非常好
It's so the idea
这是个主意
So here's the block that we want to free
所以这是我们想要释放的块
And here's its header
这是它的头部
And we pass the p to it and we want to free it
我们将 p 传递给它，我们想要释放它
And we've got one bit we know that
而且我们知道
If we have a 8 byte alignment
如果我们有 8 字节对齐
We know that these are all implicitly zero
我们知道这些都隐含为零
So we're using this is a allocated block that we want to free so it has an allocation status of 1
这是一个我们想要释放的已分配块，因此它的分配状态为 1
And let's use one of these spare bits
让我们使用其中另一个位
To indicate the allocation status of the previous block
指示前一个块的分配状态
Okay so far
好的，到目前为止
If the previous block is allocated
如果分配了前一个块
And this would be a 1
这将是 1
And when we're checking to see whether we need to coalesce
当我们检查是否需要合并时
We just check that we just check that
我们只是检查一下
That that's 2nd allocated bit the allocated bit of the previous block
第二个分配位，它表示前一个块的分配位
And if it's 1 we don't need to know what its size is
如果它是 1，我们不需要知道它的大小
Okay we don't need to know where that block is because we're not going to coalesce it
我们不需要知道那个块在哪里，因为我们不打算合并它
Okay so in that we don't need
好的，我们不需要
So here we don't need a boundary tag for an allocated block
所以在已分配的块中我们不需要边界标记
But now if that block is free
但现在，如果该块是空闲的
It'll have a boundary tag
它将有一个边界标记
So we'll check if that block is free
所以我们将检查该块是否是空闲的
Then the allocation status will indicate free
然后分配状态将表示空闲
And then we know we need to, we need to coalesce
然后我们知道我们需要，我们需要合并
And we're going to need
而我们将需要
We're going to need a boundary tag, because we need to know where that block starts we need to know its size
我们需要一个边界标记，因为我们需要知道该块开始的位置，我们需要知道它的大小
So that we can go back and
这样我们就可以回去了
And update this size to include the you know the total coalesce size of those two blocks
并更新此大小为两个块的总合并大小
So is that clear yes
清楚吗
Oh it's just the allocated bit so
哦，它只是分配的位
Zero means not allocated one means allocated
0 意味着没有分配，1 表示已分配
[student speaking]
Oh why are those bits that are why are the bits always zero why
哦，为什么这些位为什么位总是为零
Okay so blocks have to be aligned to 8 byte boundaries
好的，所以块必须与 8 字节边界对齐
Okay payloads have to be aligned to 8 byte boundaries
有效载荷必须与 8 字节边界对齐
Okay that means that blocks have to be the size of blocks has to be a multiple of 8
这意味着块的大小必须是 8 的倍数
Because it's the same thing as when we were doing padding alignment instructs
因为它与我们进行填充对齐指示时的情况相同
The next each block has to be a size has to be a multiple of eight
每个块的大小必须是八的倍数
So that the block that follows that in memory is aligned properly
这样在内存中的块就可以正确对齐
Okay so you're guaranteed because of the alignment requirement
因为你需要保证字节对齐
You're guaranteed that of 8 or 16, you're guaranteed that the size of the blocks are always multiples of either 8 or 16
你需要保证块的大小总是 8 或 16 的倍数
So that because that size is always a multiple of 8 or 16
因此，因为该大小始终是 8 或 16 的倍数
You're guaranteed that either 3 or 4 bits are all zeros
你可以保证 3 位或 4 位都是零
Okay
好的
Any other questions
还有其他问题吗
Okay let me summarize then some key policies
好吧，让我总结一些关键策略
When implementing an allocator
实现分配器时
And I mentioned that there's the design spaces for these things is really large and really interesting
我提到这些东西的设计空间非常大而且非常有趣
There's a lot of things that you a lot of decisions that you have to make about various policies
你需要做出很多关于各种策略的决定
So the first is the placement policy where
首先是「放置策略」
When we're trying to find,when we're trying to place a free block
当我们试图找到，当我们试图放置一个空闲块时
I mean and out
我的意思是
When we're trying to place an allocated block somewhere in a free block somewhere in the list
当我们尝试将已分配的块放在列表中某个空闲块中的位置时
What policy do we use first fit next fit or best fit
我们使用的策略有 「首次适配」、「下一次适配」以及「最佳适配」
And generally these things they trade-off throughput for fragmentation
通常这些东西权衡碎片的吞吐量
All right so the faster versions like
所以更快的版本
If you're willing to deal with lower throughput like in the case of best fit
如果你愿意像最佳适配的情况那样处理较低的吞吐量
Then you can get better memory utilization
然后你可以获得更好的内存利用率
Now there are interesting ways to improve the performance of best fit
有一些有趣的方法可以提高最佳适配的性能
You might consider something like good fit
你可能会考虑一些如「不错的适配」的方案
Which is sort of a mix of first fit and best fit so maybe
这可能首次适配和最佳适配的混合
Maybe you only search the first
也许你只搜索第一个
You know a portion of the heap and then identify the best fit
搜索堆的一部分，然后确定最合适的
You know maybe instead of searching the entire heap
也许不是搜索整个堆
You just search some portion of the heap
你只需搜索堆的某些部分
And then cut off the search and then within that region that you search do you pick the best block
然后切断搜索，然后在你搜索的区域内选择最佳区块
So that's something that called good fit
所以这就是所谓的「不错的适配」
So that kind of approximates best fit
所以这种接近于最佳适配
Or you can use these multiple free lists to approximate best fit
或者你可以使用多个空闲列表来近似你和最佳适配
And the real advantage of using multiple free lists
而且使用多个空闲列表的真正优势
Is that it not only improves memory utilization
是它不仅提高了内存利用率
But it improves performance too because the individual lists that you're looking for
它也提高了性能，因为你正在寻找的特定的列表
You know that they contain blocks that are close to what you're asking for
你知道它们包含的块与你要求的块接近
And since you're dividing all the free blocks up among multiple free lists
而且，因为你将所有的空闲块分割到多个空闲列表中
Those free lists will be shorter
那些空闲列表会更短
Okay so your searches will take less time
好的，所以你的搜索将花费更少的时间
And your probability of finding a block that fits goes up
你找到适合的块的概率会上升
Because you're segregating these different size classes
因为你要隔离这些不同大小的类
Now we also have to decide on some splitting policy so
.我们还必须决定一些分裂策略
We find a free block that's big enough
我们找到一个足够大的空闲块时
What do we do with the leftover part of that block
我们如何处理该块的剩余部分
You know once we placed an allocated block into that free block
一旦我们将一个已分配的块放入该空闲块中
What do we do with the leftovers do we just leave the leftover part
我们如何处理剩下的部分。我们丢下剩下的部分不管？
In the block itself and return that back to the application
在块本身并将其返回给应用程序
You know avoiding so that  sort of keeping larger blocks
你知道避免这种情况以便保持更大的块
Or do we go ahead and split it like I showed before
或者我们继续像以前一样分开它
And splitting we go ahead and splitting that block and creating the original free block
然后我们继续拆分该块并创建原始空闲块
Allocating a portion of it and then creating a smaller free block
分配一部分，然后创建一个较小的空闲块
So that's you know that's a policy we may you may want to
所以这是我们可能想要的策略
You may want to for small requests for small payloads
以针对小型有效负载的小请求
You may up to a certain size,you may not want to split,so you may not you may decide not to split blocks smaller
以达到块的大小有一定的下限，不把块继续分割成更小的块的目的
You may decide not to create free blocks that are smaller than some threshold
你可能决定不创建小于某个阈值的空闲块
And only splitting for requests for larger blocks
并且仅针对更大块的请求进行拆分
And then the there's a coalescing policy
然后是一个合并政策
Now we've seen freeing is pretty quick now it's constant time because of the boundary tag footers
现在我们已经看到释放非常快，因为边界标记，这个过程是常数时间
But you may want to
但你可能想要
You may want to try to just speed that up even more by deferring the coalescing
你可能希望通过延迟合并来尝试加快速度
So you can do coalescing it
所以你可以
Every time the free is called like we just looked at
和我们刚才看到的一样，当每次 free 被调用时就进行合并
Or you could defer coalescing to some later time
或者你可以推迟到某个时间再进行合并
You know maybe when you're scanning the free list
当你在扫描空闲列表时
When you're scanning the free list looking
当你正在扫描空闲列表时
Trying to find, trying to place an allocated block in response to a malloc call
尝试查找，尝试放置已分配的块以响应 malloc 调用
Maybe as you scan that free list you could go ahead and do the coalescing at that time
也许当你扫描该空闲列表时，你可以继续进行当时的合并
Right so I'm not saying which one is better it's really hard to argue for
所以我不是说哪一个更好，这真的很难争辩
Deferred coalescing and giving the constant time performance of a boundary tag-based coalescing
延迟合并以及给出基于边界标签的合并的恒定时间性能
But it is an option
但这是一种选择
Okay so here's the summary then of implicit lists
好的，这里是隐式列表的总结
This is the simplest well
这是最简单
It's a very simple kind of allocator
这是一种非常简单的分配器
It's...
它的...
The cost to allocate is linear in the size of the heap worst case
在最坏情况下，分配器的成本是与堆的大小呈线形关系的
That the cost of free is constant time even with coalescing
即使合并，free 的成本也是恒定的时间
Memory usage will depend on the placement policy first fit ,next fit or best fit
内存使用情况取决于放置策略 —— 「首次适配」、「下一次适配」以及「最佳适配」
Um it's not used in practice
它没有在实践中使用
Because of the linear time, the linear time cost of allocation
由于分配的线性时间成本
Okay but it can be used in sort of special-purpose
好的，但它可以用于某种特殊目的
Allocators where you have a small number of size classes maybe or
你可以选择具有少量尺寸等级的分配器
You have a very you know that you have a very small or a fairly small free list
或者你有一个非常小或相当小的空闲列表
But the ideas of splitting and coalescing that we looked at are general to all allocators
但是进行了分割和合并的想法对于所有的分配器都适用
Okay so the idea of a boundary tag boundary tag-based coalescing
基于边界标签边界的合并的想法
Is used regardless of the structure of your free list
无论你的空闲列表的结构如何都会被使用
So implicit lists are useful to study
所以隐式列表对于学习非常有用
Because they introduce some important concepts
因为他们介绍了一些重要概念
But generally they're not that useful
但一般来说它们并没有那么有用
So next class we'll look at some more sophisticated organizations of free list
所以下一节课我们将看一些更复杂的空闲列表
The explicit list and multiple free lists in particular
显示列表和特别是多个空闲列表
Alright so we'll see you then, good luck on your shell lab due tonight
好吧，所以我们会见到你，祝你今晚的 shell 实验好运
And we'll see you on Thursday
我们星期四见